# Eva Sharma

Tech Square Research Building (341A) 85 Fifth Street NW, Atlanta GA 30308

Aug 2016 - Present

GPA 4.0 / 4.0

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in the area of computational social sciences and I aim to leverage computational methods and resources in order to understand and reason about complex social processes underlying human behavior in large-scale online social systems.

**Topics**: Social Computing, Computational Social Science, Large-Scale Data Analysis, Online Communities, Online Social Support

## **EDUCATION**

Georgia Institute Of Technology, Atlanta, GA Doctor of Philosophy, Advisor: Munmun De Choudhury Computer Science.

Cornell University, Ithaca, NY
Masters of Engineering,
Computer Science.

Aug 2014 - May 2015
GPA 3.9 / 4.0

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA

Bachelors of Technology (Semester Abroad Program),

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.

Aug 2011 - Jan 2012

GPA 5.0 / 5.0

SRM University, Chennai, TN, India
Bachelors of Technology,
Computer Science (Gold Medalist).

July 2009 - May 2013
GPA 9.9 / 10.0

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Analyzing Ideological discourse on Social Media: A Case Study of the Abortion Debate
Submitted to ICWSM 2017.

Eva Sharma, Koustuv Saha, Sindhu Kiranmai Ernala, Sucheta Ghoshal, Munmun De Choudhury

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Oracle, Cambridge, MA

Software Developer II

July 2015 - Aug 2016

• Implemented Multiple Payment and Address Book Module for Mobile Commerce iOS Application

# SAP Labs India Pvt. Ltd. Bangalore, India

Associate Developer

July 2013 - July 2014

- Worked on Software Logistics Process Repository for Lifecycle Management of SAP Software
- Designed and implemented installation and update feature for HANA Application Lifecycle Management
- Co-Implemented delete and copy stack backend functionality for Cross Product Stack Editor

Feb. 2013 - June 2013

- Analyzed Customer Profile Data in XML format by automating processing of XMLs and feeding them to HANA database where the data can be later visualized as graphs
- Built an interface which utilizes gestures and voice to interact with computers.

#### **TEACHING**

## Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

Spring 2015

Teaching Assistant

Prof. Lucja Kot, CS 4320/5320 Introduction to Database System

#### **PROJECTS**

# Semantic Legal Information System's

## Legal Text Indexing Application

Sara S. Frug, Legal Information Institute, Cornell University

- Studied and experimented with Topic Modeling for CFR Corpus
- Used metadata from CFR and FR corpus to capture evolution of a topic over time
- Employed incremental modeling and phrase extraction using Mallet

# Computing a statistical description of 3-D structure of nano-scale biological objects

Jan. 2015 - May. 2015

Prof. Peter Charles Doerschuk, Cornell University

- Helped providing python conversion of MATLAB equivalent of fmincon, which solves nonlinear programming problems, fundamentally computing the location of the minimum value of a user-provided function
- Applied MATLAB version of the project to example problems to determine the input values for each of the project's functions and the returned values.
- Wrote unit test cases in python to perform extensive testing for the python version of the project

## **Sound Source Localization**

Sep. 2011 - Dec. 2011

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Prof. James R Glass, Spoken Language System Group, CSAIL

- Studied various techniques being used for 2-D acoustic localization
- Implemented GCC-PHAT method to localize sound using two microphones MATLAB

## ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- Undergraduate Gold Medalist, Awarded by The Prime Minister of India, Mr. Narendra Modi
- Undergraduate Toppers Scholarship, Perfect GPA of 10.0/10.0 Award for 3<sup>rd</sup>, 6<sup>th</sup> and 8<sup>th</sup> semesters
- Undergraduate sponsorship for a semester abroad at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA

# **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Presented poster on "Quantifying Well-Being Support to Assess Efficacy of Online Communities" in GVU Fall Research Showcase 2016, Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Presented poster on "Semantic Legal Information Systems Improving Access to Regulatory Information" in BOOM 2015 (BITS ON OUR MINDS), Cornell University.
- Volunteered for Product Innovation Day Event in SAP Labs, Bangalore.
- Participated in Hadoop Tech Talk conducted at Exebit 2012, IIT Madras.
- Participated in Ethical Hacking and Information Security Workshop by Kyrion Technologies.
- Organized Paper Presentation event held at Infoyez11, SRM University, Chennai.

Oct. 2014 - Dec. 2014